KINJAL PARIKH

https://KinjalParikh.github.io Kinjal.Parikh@outlook.com \diamond (437)-973-1393 222 Elm Street, Toronto, Canada (M5T1K5)

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research area is computer graphics and I am particularly interested in geometry processing. My current focus is on computing shape descriptors for analysis of 3D geometry. To this end, I am working on computing higher-order derivatives through the application of multilinear algebra.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto

Sept 2022 - Present

PhD in Computer Science at Dynamic Graphics Project

Advised by Prof. David Levin

Savitribai Phule Pune University

2017 - 2021

B. Tech. in Computer Engineering

RESEARCH

Summer Geometry Institute, Massachusetts Institute of Technology

July 2021 - Aug 2021

Summer Research Program

Acceptance rate: 5.4 %

Topic: Optimal Interlocking Parts via Implicit Shape Optimizations Mentor: Professor David Levin, Dept. of Computer Science, University of Toronto

· Topic: Self-similarity loss for shape descriptor learning in correspondence problems Mentor: Dr. Tal Schnitzer, Dept. of Computer Science, Massachusetts Institute of Technology

· Topic: Learning Classifiers of Parametric Implicit Functions

Mentor: Dr. Matheus Gadelha, Adobe Research

Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

May 2020 - July 2021

B. Tech. Research Project

Topic: Formalization of Translation Performed by the SCLP compiler phases

Advisor: Professor Uday Khedker, Dept. of Computer Engineering

(SCLP is a language processor used to teach UG courses CS302+CS316 at IIT Bombay)

- · Developed a novel model of compilation that focuses on the intermediate representations produced by a compiler and their step-wise refinement.
- · Created specifications for two intermediate representations and for the translation between them.
- · Built a transpiler that can generate C++ code for translation between two intermediate representations from the translation specification we created

EXPERIENCE

University of Toronto

Sept 2023 - present

Teaching Assistant

· CSC108H1: Introduction to Computer Programming

Walmart Global Tech India

Aug 2021 - Aug 2022

Software Engineer

· Worked on several Java Springboot projects for logistic systems used in international markets.

Walmart Global Tech India

June 2020 - July 2020

Summer Intern

· Contributed to a project automating the calculation of key performance indicators for workflows. Used PySpark and Microsoft SQL.

Excellon Software July 2019

Summer Intern

· Worked on creating a customer support chatbot.

AWARDS AND SCHOLARSHIPS

Wolfond Scholarship Program in Wireless Information Technology

2022-2024

University of Toronto

20,000 CAD

Seminar report on Scene Graph Generation

2020

Cummins College of Engineering

top 15 (out of 224) student seminars

Lady Ada National Programming Contest for Women

2019

ACM-W India

among top 10 finalists

Code-It Intra-college coding competition

2019, 2018

ACM-W College Chapter

1st rank

National Creative Aptitude Test

2018

International Forum for Excellence in Higher Education

all India 99.5th percentile in 1st round

PROJECTS

NeRF April 2023

· Reimplemented 'Nerf: Representing scenes as neural radiance fields for view synthesis'

Quasi-harmonic weights

Dec 2022

Reimplemented the paper 'Fast Quasi-Harmonic Weights for Geometric Data Interpolation' by Yu Wang and Justin Solomon - using Python.

Normal-Driven Spherical Shape Analogies

July 2021

· Reimplemented the paper 'Normal-Driven Spherical Shape Analogies' by Hsueh-Ti Derek Liu and Alec Jacobson - using MATLAB.

Virtual Drumkit May 2020

· Developed an application that simulates a Drumkit using OpenCV.

Augmented Reality Photo Booth App

Fen 2020

· Developed an Android application using Sceneform framework that allows users to take pictures with virtual 3D objects.

OUTREACH

Summer Geometry Institute - student volunteer

July 2023

- · Organized social events
- · Assisted students in their projects and coordinated with project mentors

Samyak Drishti Foundation NGO

2017 - 2020

- · Taught basic English course to underprivileged school girls
- · Organized and participated in various environmental and social drives.

Hour of Code Dec 2018

· Volunteered in a drive for encouraging children to participate in computer science related activities.